JENNIFER MOORE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

contact@jenniferplusplus.com 1-817-264-7347 https://jenniferplusplus.com

I support engineering teams to grow and become very high performing and effective by fostering psychological safety and engineering best practices. I prefer to work in a high trust, highly autonomous environment so that I can lead my team in iteratively improving that process to make it faster, safer, and more sustainable. I'm seeking to grow or support a trusting and collaborative culture where we can all do our best engineering work.

SKILLS

SOFTWARE C#, .NET, JAVASCRIPT/TYPESCRIPT, NODE.JS, SQL, DOCKER, KUBERNETES,

DEVELOPMENT GOLANG, TDD/BDD

DEVOPS CI/CD, OPENTELEMETRY, GIT, GITHUB ACTIONS, AWS, GCP

SDLC TFS, JIRA, AGILE, SCRUM, KANBAN, GITHUB

PROJECTS

Letterbook, Maintainer (open source) (Open source)

ActivityPub C# Asp.net core Postgres Self-hosted OpenTelemetry

Letterbook is a federated microblogging service, implementing ActivityPub. The goal for the project is to make hosting a fediverse server a better and more sustainable experience. We also want to make it a safer and more inclusive space for the people who make the fediverse their social media home.

I began Letterbook in the 2nd half of 2023 as an alternative to Mastodon and other federated social media apps, with a focus on low cost, easy operations, and an inviting stance for other contributors. It's grown to have 5 or 6 semi-regular contributors and is nearing an alpha release. As the project creator and core maintainer, I've done the large majority of the technical work, of course. Beyond that, I've focussed on recruiting, on-boarding, and coordinating other contributors to create a long-term collaborative project.

- Federated microblogging platform, similar to Mastodon or Bluesky
- Flexible architecture to support, small single server deployments that can grow as-needed to high-capacity, high-availability, distributed systems
- Emphasis on observability, to enable independent admins to understand and manage their own software, and to better investigate problems when they arise
- Small but growing community of contributors
- Admins and moderators are a first-class priority
- Optimizing for performance on low cost, low powered hardware and global mobile networks and devices; targeting world-wide accessibility

Castify Studio, DevOps (professional) (Professional)

Node.js OpenTelemetry GCP Postgres Docker Kubernetes Feature flags Github Actions

The new Castify Studio product is a 2nd generation of Screencastify's core screen-recording app. This evolves the product from a standalone application into a complete service, which provides a much better experience for the basic record/edit/share workflow, and will enable the company to support a much richer set of features going forward.

I led the DevOps and SRE effort in the lead up to release and beyond. In my time here, I shifted the DevOps team away from a purely reactive catchall group doing infrastructure toil, to one that actively makes improvements to the workflows and process of the whole engineering organization. I put heavy emphasis on reliability, the developer experience including speed and reliability of CICD, the observability of our systems, and ease and safety of deployment.

- Containerized architecture in GCP
- Mix of client-server request-response work, and dynamically scaled asynchronous processing mediated through a task queue in kubernetes
- Emphasis on observability; logs, metrics, traces, with the goal of making system behavior understandable and discoverable
- Docker compose based local development workflow, including traces and log collection
- Feature flags; enabling more rapid and controlled deployments, and as a tool to support operations, customer success, and product decision
- Blame-aware incident response and retrospectives focussed on building team confidence to participate in future

EMPLOYMENT

Staff Software Engineer, Influxdata

2023-03 — Present

Influxdata is the company behind InfluxDB, a leading time series database for sensors, metrics, and IoT workloads. I've built and supported internal dev tools and CI/CD infrastructure. I've also supported the development, packaging, deployment, and operations of the on-prem and hosted single-tenant database products.

Staff Software Engineer, DevOps, Screencastify

2022-05 — 2023-01

Screencastify makes a screen recording application that's popular in k12 education. I joined to grow DevOps practices and culture within the engineering organization, and I think I've been very successful in doing so. This has been a great team and a great experience, where I've been able to put into practice many aspects of a DevOps working model that have been mostly theoretical for me in the past.

Staff Software Engineer, Instil

2021-09 — 2022-03

Instil is an early-stage startup that unfortunately did not have the product-market fit they thought they did when I joined. I tried to promote sustainable and effective development practices to support the team. At the same time, I also developed multiple significant features for their CRM product. But ultimately the unpredictability of searching for a market fit wasn't a good situation for me.

Senior Software Engineer, Charles Schwab

2019-08 — 2021-08

I joined Schwab as the technical lead for a development team in the Retail Web Technology group. I worked on multiple projects, including a greenfield customer-facing cash transfer app. On that and other projects, I worked closely with designers and product owners and other development teams working in parallel to build backend services and mobile features.

Senior Software Engineer, Solera/Title Tech

2018-10 — 2019-08

At Solera, I worked on customer facing products dealing with state and local laws, taxes, and fees related to vehicle sales, registration, and titling. I advocated for greater adoption of engineering best practices, especially surrounding continuous testing and deployment. I also coordinated with other teams in designing new service oriented architectures.

Senior Software Engineer, Allegro Development

2017-11 — 2018-09

At Allegro I led an overseas team in designing and building new features for Allegro's main product, Horizon. I also pushed to advance best practices including unit testing and DevOps.

Senior Software Engineer, ParkHub

2017-03 — 2017-09

At Parkhub, I built a new generation of services and infrastructure for a sensor-based parking lot monitoring service. I utilized IoT sensors, containerized microservices, and Kubernetes.

Senior Software Engineer, Fidelity Investments

2014-06 — 2017-03

As a software engineer, led multiple very successful automated testing efforts. I also played a central role in the design and implementation of customer facing and middle tier applications. I promoted best practices and mentored junior team members throughout these projects.

EDUCATION

BS Software Engineering, University of Texas at Arlington

2006-09 — 2010-06

Majored in Software Engineering, no degree

Director, Women Who Code DFW

2020-05 — 2020-10

As a director, I was a member of the official leadership team for the DFW network of Women Who Code. I planned and organized monthly events; I coordinated with the hosts, sponsors, and presenters during the event; I recruited new hosts and speakers; and I helped to grow and mentor future members of the WWC DFW leadership team.

Player, Dungeons & Dragons

2000-10 — Present

I've been playing and running D&D and other tabletop role playing games regularly for over 20 years. Through that hobby, I've gained a great deal of experience in working with small groups toward a common goal. Among other things, that includes: quickly learning and teaching complex systems, sharing focus and responsibility with the group, and finding balance between working toward a goal and enabling discovery.